I have a wonderful story about teaching
我有一个关于教学的美妙故事，
that I wish could be multiplied many times over.
我希望它能被放大许多倍。
It comes from a memoir of a man
故事来自于 20 世纪早期
who grew up in Harlem in the earlier
在哈林区长大的
part of the 20th century.
一个男人的回忆录。
And he writes in his memoir about the great
他在回忆录中写到了当时
difficulties of being a child in Harlem at that time.
在哈林区作为一个孩子的巨大困难。
But about the one or two public school teachers
但是，有一两个公立学校的老师改变了他的生活，
who lifted his life and he tells an especially touching
他讲述了一个关于波特先生的特别感人的故事，
story about Mr. Porter who was his black math teacher.
这位波特是他的黑人数学老师。
And this the memoirist writes that he the person
这位回忆录作者写道，
writing the memoir was apparently born
他这个写回忆录的人显然
with an inability to calculate and to count.
天生就不会计算和计数。
But he says Mr. Porter took his failure very well,
但他说，作为一名数学老师的波特先生
as a math teacher.
欣然接受了他的失败。
And stopped trying to teach this young man math
波特先生不再试图教这个年轻人数学，
and instead assigned him to write an article
而是指派他为学生报纸
for the student newspaper about Harlem.
写一篇关于哈林区的文章。
He took him to the public library,
他带他去公共图书馆，
he helped him pour over his writing,
帮助他倾心写作，
he helped him develop his craft,
帮助他发展手艺，
abandon the teaching of mathematics altogether,
完全放弃了数学教学，
because he perceived in this
因为他在这个孩子身上
child a gift that no one else had seen.
察觉到了别人没有看到的天赋。
The writer of that memoir is James Baldwin
那本回忆录的作者是詹姆斯 · 鲍德温，
and having read that I cannot get out of my mind
读了这本书后，我脑海中无法忘怀
the image of the courageous teacher who is willing
那个勇敢的老师的形象，
to give up the technical subject,
他愿意放弃技术科目，
to give up passing the test in that subject
放弃在最后通过该科目的考试，
at the end of the road and to look instead at
而是着眼于
the child and the child's gifts.
这个孩子及其天赋，
Without teachers like that, we're going to lose
如果没有这样的老师，随着时间的推移，
a lot of James Baldwin's as the years go by
我们将失去很多像詹姆斯 · 鲍德温这样的学生，
and we don't want to do that.
而我们不想这样做。